i appreciate y'all so good to be here
byu country oh you know right huh
i'm a big football fan right i'm an
auburn tiger war eagle i gotta put i
gotta all my family's alabama i actually
come from a long line of disabilities
because i stutter my father was blind
and my mother and brother are alabama
fans so uh
man it's been tough it's been tough and
my daddy really was blind that's a true
story uh my parents divorced when i was
two he moved to a different town every
year at christmas my mother would give
me twenty dollars to go buy my blind
alabama fan father a christmas present
and i remember going down to this store
and i bought him this awesome auburn
sweatshirt
and he wore that thing around for three
weeks saying wrong time
i ought to be ashamed of myself but i'm
not not not worth her but it's cool been
here because i mean you guys have a
great history i was a little boy i love
me some steve young man i mean i love
you know
auburn had the great running backs like
bo jackson and he was like me comes he
stuttered it was so kind of like bo
stutters and then two years before that
hershey walker was in georgia and he
stuttered who i'm like well obviously if
you stutter you're going to be a
football player
so i was the starting quarterback for my
opelika junior high school football team
in 1985 and i'll never forget the first
game of the year we were down by five we
had all three timeouts left but i knew
that i was gonna be able to drive my
team down for that winning score and
they're gonna carry me off the field
like rudy it was gonna be the best thing
ever i'm like yeah man i remember i got
behind my center and and and and
and they call me for delay again
[Applause]
so they backed us up five yards i got
behind him again and i did and i dropped
out of pass and him my best friend
adrian's telling my best friend today
hit him over the middle for a 14-yard
gain i ran him to the referee i said
timeout
i time out
he charges all three timeouts
[Laughter]
we lost the game
that was my first and last start but uh
that's okay i wouldn't
meant to be a football player but but
but but it it's all cool i i need to
let you know right about that this
stutter is a hundred percent real but
for some of the storytelling purposes i
do
fake the stutter somebody say he doesn't
really start her trust me my mama says
jody we'll never forget your first word
yeah we don't know what in the world you
said
but it had about 12 syllables we thought
you were going to be a genius of
something
[Laughter]
i try to bring awareness to stuttering
through humor that's what and one of the
biggest pet peeves for people who
stutter is when people want to finish
our sentences for us and a lot of times
i don't care but sometimes i do care i
was flying out to las vegas for a gig uh
a couple of years ago and i was sitting
next to a sweet lady and she wasn't
trying to be ugly she just didn't know
any better but she asked me she said so
where are you staying i said i'm staying
at the um
mgm i said no ma'am no ma'am i said i'm
saying that
she said mirage i said no ma'am not
there either
i said i'm saying
she said monte carlo i said lady this
ain't named that tune you ain't gonna
win nothing
i'm staying at the bellagio
i was really staying at mandalay bay but
she didn't need to know all that stuff
but uh
i love stutter man i've been blessed to
to be published by chicken soup for the
soul eight times and one of my my
stories in a book is called embracing my
uniqueness and you know we all have some
type of uni of uniqueness that that that
that that that that that
some people may see it as a flaw but you
got to take it and grab it and make it
your own because there's a silver lining
to everything grew up really
really poor and
and and every year at christmas in my
hometown true story santa claus would
set up a trailer at the local shopping
center
i thought everybody lived in trailers
why not santa claus you know
it's got a lot of insulation in there
behind the the wood paneling walls and
the green shack carpet from the late 70s
and i remember my mama dropped me and my
brother off and i guess we caught santa
claus off guard because when i opened up
the door to the trailer he had his beard
now smoking a lucky strike
and he said
look he stuttered too
he said little boy what are you up for
christmas i said santa let me let me get
a skate skate skate skate skate
skateboard so i ran in the christmas
morning had eight skateboards under the
tree
best christmas of all time right there
no
doubt about it but but i mean but but i
mean i you know i have my challenges uh
uh uh when i travel i like to eat like
i've eaten some good places here but
when i'm on the highway i don't know why
i like to get a fish sandwich from
mcdonald's right now i have trouble uh
it can be any letter in the alphabet but
it's usually f words and s words
but i am a clean comedian
always a clean company but f words and s
words really get me really bad uh uh but
when i travel i like to get a fish
sandwich from mcdonald's i don't know
why they're disgusting they're greasy
sometimes it's got that hard little
little bouncy thing you know you know
i probably have four or five of them on
my floorboard now
nevertheless i go there and and and
y'all i can stand right here in front of
y'all this evening and i can say fish
sandwich fish sandwich fish sandwich
fish sandwich for sandwich food sandwich
but you put me at that drive through
window there's gonna be a line i can
assure you
because i pulled up to the i was in
aurora colorado a couple weeks ago i
pulled up to the drive-through wounded
there and the girl's like can i take
your order i said yes ma'am let me have
a
she said excuse me
i said yes ma'am let me have one
she said you're gonna have to repeat
that i said i'm trying
i said yes man let me have one
chicken sandwich please hold the mayo
and you think they mess up your
drive-through i get like six orders of
fries i said ma'am i did not order six
orders of fries she said right here on
the receipt fry fry fry fry fry
i said that's only five
[Laughter]
so it's got the challenges there i i
never knew what i was going to do in
life my father uh was a barber uh
y'all are good listeners
i can appreciate that before he lost his
eyesight
i i that's really cool i'm glad you
y'all are a smart crowd i can
i can appreciate that my mother uh
worked in a box factory for 37 years a
lover she's she's still here she missed
work one day the whole time i lived
under her
roof and it's like so it's a gr great
family and
and and my father he taught me to ride a
bicycle you know he was blind but he he
still did the things that the father
would do he taught me to work
ride a bicycle let me just tell you when
you cross a blind father
a stuttering kid
and bicycle lessons
bad things are bound to happen
because i remember he he he he he had
his hand on the back seat here had his
other hand on the handlebar here and
he's pushing me just as fast as ah
as he can but before i could get out the
word stop
i was face first in the sticker bushes
but the good thing about that is that i
learned to ride that bike real fast
but i never knew what i was going to do
when i was a little
well uh uh
uh 15 years old i started working at a
little grocery store then when i was 16
i hit the big time y'all i started
working at kroger
big time
and i was actually in a little drugstore
we had the kroger drug store here then
there was a solid wall then on this side
over here you had the big kroger and we
got a brand new kroger on the other side
of town now and and i was actually
riding by there the other day
with my best friend adrian the guy threw
that that pass to and we're riding down
the road and i'm over there he's driving
and
and i'm playing on my phone whatever i'm
doing here and and he said jody i said
what's up he said do you think that car
in front of us drove all the way up here
from ecuador
i said what are you talking about he
said you you see the tag it says ecuador
and we got to the traffic light and i
looked real hard and i said dude that
says educator
obviously he did not have that tag on
his car
we were bothering you but i worked at
the old kroger and i was at the little
drugstore and i love people i i love
people i love customers and
they knew me and i knew them but we're
in the little drugstore so we had the
cash register here and we had a counter
over here and and and and a lot of
things were behind the counter uh like
perfume and and film and batteries
things that had a habit of walking out
of the store we had to keep behind the
counter so i'm running the cash register
one day and there's a sweet old lady at
the end of the counter and she's down
there spraying cologne and perfume with
both hands she's got a big mist above
her head like los angeles and and i said
i said ma'am can i help you she said yes
sir i'm looking for some perfume that i
saw last week but now i can't find it i
said okay do you remember what it was
called she said yes sir it was called
tester
you get the big bottle or the little
model
and i have in a variety of colors too
but
i i love my customers this one here i i
i i'm convinced y'all are gonna
get it i usually preface it by saying
half of you are gonna get it right now
the other half of you may get it
tomorrow after lunch but y'all are a
smart crowd there's some places i go to
but i i trust so a guy he comes there
he's coughing sneezing head hurts no
stopped up you name it he's got it but
the thing is he he he he he told me he
only had two dollars to his name and he
could not sleep that was his biggest
issues there dude also his name and he
could not sleep so i go to the back and
i showed him kroger's version of nyquil
called night time that's key kroger's
version of nyquil is called nighttime
and it was 1.79 plus tax back in the day
so i go back there and i show it to him
called night time and he immediately
looked at it and said oh man i said
what's up he said i can't take this i
said why not he said man i work third
shift
[Laughter]
they'll get it later on
that's my favorite now now there was
another guy that that came into the
store one day and and he too had a
speech impediment and he became a great
friend of mine and he has given me the
express written consent to tell this
story although all the times i don't
want anybody thinking i'm making fun of
the of of this guy but but he had a
speech he put him too and he's down at
the end of the perfume and cologne
counter and he's stretching as far as he
can he can almost reach what he's trying
to get but he's coming up a little bit
short and i said sir can i help you he
said yeah let me have a bottle of your
old pies
i said do what he said let me have a
bottle of your old pies right there in a
red bottle i said oh oh spice he said
yeah i have trouble with my s words i'm
like i do too brother i got you so i
reached back there and i picked up the
only thing of old spice
cologne that we had and he looked at it
and said hmm i said what is it he said
uh
this is the prion do you have the
pleasure
[Laughter]
i said do what
he said this is the prey on do you have
to place your own because i like to
place it on my ken
i'm liking they don't mind
[Music]
do you go to family reunions like bam
bam
know where you are this weekend
i said no sir no certain notes are all i
have all i have all i have is uh uh uh
uh i i i i is the prey on so
he said well do you have the old pisce
deodorant i said yes i would do us on
the back wall somewhere all the way to
the back wall of kroger picked up the
only thing cause again this is just the
little drugstore the only thing of old
spice deodorant that we had and he
looked at it and said hmm
i said what is it he said uh this is the
tick do you have the roll on
i said no sir all i have is a tick
then he said well i don't like the tick
called a tick get tucked to your hair
and it does get
tucked it's like christmas lights
oh man i love working there uh i
remember one cold december night in
alabama cold
it was like 50. and uh
almost christmas lady comes there and
says young man i said yes ma'am she said
where are your ointments so i took her
back and i showed her the creams the
sads salves eliminates she said no silly
your christmas ointments
[Laughter]
i love one of my favorite stories a
sweet old lady came into the store one
night and i had known her my whole life
she lived up the road for me when i was
a kid named
miss helen and miss helen had been a
widow for about 10 years she came to the
store one night looking just just
gorgeous had her hair all fixed up
looked very nice and i said miss helen
what's the occasion you know you look
great she said jody
i'm looking for a man
so i took a step backwards and uh
it miss helen what kind of man are you
looking for she said jody i'm not
looking for a man with good looks i said
well that's good miss hell what kind of
man are you looking for she said jody
i'm not looking for um a man of money i
said well that's good mr helen what kind
of man are you looking for she said jody
i'm looking for a man who can drive at
night
[Laughter]
get a little bit older you know
i speak to all kind of groups and stuff
and i was speaking to some some school
employees and uh there was uh about 19
ladies and one gentleman in the crowd i
told that story got a good chuckle and
this guy was probably late 50s early 60s
got a chuckle then it got all quiet all
of a sudden this guy leaned back in this
chair slipped off his glasses lit right
and said
i can drive at night
like that's that's that's my guy right
there is who i want to be one day but uh
man but i love working there again so so
so many great people uh uh about halfway
through my time working there they
actually knocked a hole in the wall
where you could go over into the big
kroger so a guy comes in there when i
said jody where do you keep your plums i
saw it over there to the hole in the
wall and i pointed to where it is in
basically every grocery store in america
i said halfway in that wall he cannot
miss this right there and he walks over
there and he's just all over him just
i'm like just stop and stop just and he
never did so i got somebody to watch my
cash register and i ran over there as
fast as i could i said dude the plums
are right here he said no man not them
kind of plums i'm talking about what you
plumb your toilet with
but the thing is he spent 10 minutes
looking the monster squash and cucumbers
and carrots
like you would have seen the stick
picking up man
you know sometimes i say things that
just makes me feel not so smart but i
was not prepared uh
my mother never prepped me for this
question my father passed away when i
was eight years old so he he didn't
prepare and i just had no idea so i'm
working in the store when
one sunday afternoon 16 years old lady
comes into the store she says young man
i said yes ma'am how can i help you she
said where are your feminine napkins
[Laughter]
so i took her back to the paper towel
i said i think these are real pretty
[Laughter]
i had no idea
learned a lot that day
oh man i love working there man man
it's important to listen people you know
it's the plight and curtis thing to do
number two you may learn something and
number three they may say something
funny but number four it could prevent
you from getting your hind end whooped
because a guy comes to the store he's
about six foot nine three hundred pounds
looked like hulk hogan or somebody big
old scary monster of a man and i'm so
thankful that i listened i listened i
listened i listened because before i
said anything he started talking and he
asked me he asked me now
where are your q-tips
so i said
[Laughter]
[Applause]
i didn't say
anything i didn't talk for two days
he could have been lurking or something
but uh
i enjoyed that i knew i needed to do
something else and wound up going into
the army shortly after high school i
tried going to college for one quarter
but it just did not work out you heard
me say hulk hogan i've always been a
huge wrestling fan i know it's fake but
i've always loved it but but that first
quarter in college that first quarter in
college i took three classes i withdrew
from the first two and i failed the
other one
but the cool thing is that when i got
back my grades i made a wwf
i was like oh yeah
but i knew i needed to do something and
and i wound up going into the army and
when i was a young enlisted soldier i
was a an army medic was stationed in
germany for two years a place called
landstuhl big hospital over there then i
was stationed at fort sill oklahoma for
a couple of years too and i i loved it
out there i love my people i love
serving uh couldn't help but laugh
though at all the sergeants that i
served with uh uh who could not spell
the word sergeant
uh he says no
s-a-r-g-e-n-t s-e-a-r-g i'm like how in
the world can you not spell your own
rank
until i became a lieutenant
that's why i would go about ld
but i remember i i never went to the
field one time when i was in germany
then i got into foreign and we stayed in
the field all the time it's really cold
and wet and rainy and miserable there
they carried me to the field i was not
prepared my feet were like blocks of ice
i wanted to cry
and my sergeant sergeant garza who's
still a dear friend of mine this day he
said fuller next time we come out here
you go to the px and you get you some
painting holes and you put those on and
that will keep your feet warmer and you
can think literally you could thank me
later i said roger that sergeant so i
did we got back out to the px i got me
some some pantyhose got me some
knee-highs uh i got some sandal feet for
the summer i mean i was set for the year
however somewhere he told me i was
supposed to wear those pantyhose in
conjunction with ray with regular socks
somehow i missed that
because there i was running around the
woods of forza oklahoma in combat boots
and pantyhose
and not only were my feet colder
but i had blisters
and i had a run in my hose
i went to iraq three times uh after 9 11
and uh uh we had so much support from
back home uh i've got some letters that
i'd like to share with y'all these came
from some kids and uh
this is exactly the way they came and
i've got to wear my glasses now because
i can't read without them uh
i had to actually wear glasses in the
first grade even though my vision was
perfect i went to the eye doctor and he
was very impatient because he sat me in
the chair and asked me to read that
first letter on the bottom
and i got stuck on that e
and he said give him some glasses
so i wore them for three years
so that's one of the bad things about
stuttering there but uh these are
exactly the way they came and uh uh some
are funny some are sweet something like
why because they're kids and you just
you really never know what kids are
going to say but uh the first one comes
from margaret and margaret says i hope
you have good luck when you fight i
don't have any brothers or sisters so i
don't have anything to fight about
if life were so simple now here's cody
as a very inquisitive young man and
here's a little stuttering awareness
where i don't stutter when i read it's
just one of the weird things about
stuttering so cody asks
do you have any kids what do you eat are
you a man or a woman what do you rank do
you play football do you sleep in a tent
does anyone have a porsche
no horses in iraq you know this comes
from ryan who's a very optimistic young
man he says we are so glad we have such
a good army i hope we win the war in
iraq if we don't it's okay because i
know we will win the next war
anybody in here uh serving the air force
any air force in the air force it's okay
i mean it's okay
i get it but it's okay okay usually
there's air force people so so so i've
been on the search these letters came in
2000 2007 so uh i've been on the search
for a long time this comes from a young
man named corey corey says i'm in the
fifth grade if you're in the air force
do you know my second cousin bucko
jackson
the search continues
now this is going to make sense in the
long run i need you to play along
because i promise you it will make sense
in the long run so if you play along
it'll it will make sense so jessica says
knock knock
boo
[Music]
why are you crying
it's a kid it's gonna make sense i
promise
so then landon says what's up how are
you my name's landon smith i'm a boy i
hope you think i was a girl
i wrote them back said my name's jody
you read me back are you a girl
hi captain fuller my name is brianna
what's yours
hi cabin fuller thank you for fighting
in iraq what type of gun are you using
captain fuller did you fight in world
war ii
then nicki says knock knock
boo
why you crying
it's gonna make sense and then callie
you tell calais just a southern little
sassy girl cause she says
well i heard you were a comedian well i
have a crazy cat
yeah one thing to write to the soldier
seven thousand miles away
but you know i still appreciate it which
let me tell you while i'm here because
y'all are new people uh i got a crazy
cat to at home that i acquired a couple
months ago and uh she's still free to a
good home uh
three tours in iraq and i'm fine i had
to ride in a car a half hour with that
cat and i like to lost my mind
y'all ever been in the car the cat it is
the worst thing ever the cat the whole
time was real real well
all frothy at the mouth and stinking and
smelling so so so i rolled the window
down as far as it would go i have an old
car i rolled the window down
as far as it would go and it was still
round wow
so so then i said so now turn her right
up as loud as it would go but when i did
taylor swift was playing so i turned it
back off and listened to the cat
oh i got to be so me
i think taylor's awesome it's just my 13
year old she's made me listen to it so
many times so i'm like look what you
made me do so uh
i know these things right i love having
girls i'm i'm the only i'm the only guy
so it's it's it's it's fun sometimes uh
so cody says in science this week we're
talking about the human body and i hope
your human body doesn't get shot but i
got homework today
then seth says
knock knock
boo
why are you crying
ha ha ha ha
i made that up
maybe you can use in a show one day
and i did right here in provo utah
glass of cold my wife wears glasses
because she can't see i only wear them
to read but uh we're the kind of people
i don't know if y'all do it out here on
do y'all have
turtles in utah
i don't know
we have turtles all in alabama it's all
so so so we
we're the people that always stop in the
middle of the road and we stop we get
out and we help the turtle cross the
road in the direction in which it was
headed and and i usually drive just fine
but i was having a headache one day so
my wife was driving so so we're flying
down the road all of a sudden she slams
on the brakes and she turns around like
the duke boys and goes flying back i
said well then she said it's a turtle
it's a turtle it's a turtle right and we
get to she said oh my goodness it's just
a baby i said baby that's a pine cone
and she still got out and moved it
across the road
i loved it though after 9 11 i went to
officer candidate school uh uh obviously
officer candidate school at fort benning
georgia and uh
uh uh uh i got
commissioned january of 2003 one up at
fort lewis washington deployed with the
greatest men and women in the world
2003-2004 i was the platoon leader of
the third largest platoon entire united
states army just i love them i still
love them so very much but we should run
convoys all the time and at that time
only the convoy commander would have the
fancy navigational gear in his or her
vehicle so i had it in mine my sergeant
was in the lead vehicle with a strip map
drawn out so he knew we were getting
close we were going up to from where
we were up in mosul down to this place
called qs and we're going down the road
and my sergeant called him up on the
radio he said sir you got to let me know
where to turn i said roger that sergeant
i sure will so i start putting
everything in on my gps and i get it up
and everything then i get back on the
radio i said all right sergeant here's
what you need to do uh you uh uh you
need to take uh uh take take i i i take
i take uh i'll take a left he said we're
at i said about a half a click back
we blew right past that thing
but it was so great the support that we
had from back home being able to go on r
and r to just having that break all
three times i went to iraq went back to
germany for r and r and the first time i
was working so many hours a day i just
went down to bavaria i spent the whole
time down there i'll never forget
there's an american family there and and
and the mother was taking a picture of
her husband and two kids and i'm
thinking to myself you need to be in the
picture with your family that's very
very
important so i walked over there and i
asked her if she would like for me to
take the picture and i guess i was
stuttering pretty bad i don't hear at
the majority time i've been doing it for
47 years and then and but she looked at
me kind of funny but she said okay so so
she handed me her camera i took the
picture and when i did uh uh
uh she came to get it back and i handed
her the camera and she squeezed my hand
and said
you speak very good english
i said well thank you i'm from alabama i
don't hear that a whole lot
[Applause]
but the support we had from back home
just meant all the difference in the
world you know it's easier to do your
job we know people love you and support
you and respect you my grandmother was
one of our greatest supporters she would
send all kind of care packages sometimes
it didn't make a whole lot of sense at
the time but in 0.304 the mail would
take about a month to get there and the
px truck would show up and it would run
out of stuff just like that
uh one of the tricks of trade that you
do in that type of of weather 125
degrees in the summer is you get baby
powder and you put it in every nook and
cranny in your body you help to absorb
all the moisture and it just makes for a
much more pleasant day in that type of
environment well i woke up one day 125
degrees and i was out of baby powder but
then i remember my awesome wonderful
grandmother from tallapoosa county in
alabama a great southern lady in a care
package for some unknown reason she had
sent me
a five pound bag of self-rising flour
me being the sharp lieutenant that i was
i got that self-rising flower i put it
in every nook and cranny on my body and
i was good to go it was self-rising and
tingly
then we wound up going an emergency
convoy that day we're going about four
hours down the road we drop our load we
do a turn and burn we get on back to
mosul and by the time i get back i am
worn out i'm tired so i go back to my
hoops i pull off my kevlar i pull off my
flat vest i pulled off my shirt and when
i pulled off my t-shirt two biscuits
fell out
grandmama knew what she was doing
i want to thank y'all so much for making
this
[Music]
so
you